Alaa Jerbi

Software Engineering Student

Student in Software Engineering with experience in application development and design. Fluent in English with excellent writing and verbal skills. Passionate with building products that are not only useful, but also delightful to look at and use. Energetic and motivated with strong work ethic in team or individual settings.

SKILLS

Frontend Backend

JavaScript, React, React Native, TypeScript, HTML/CSS Node, PHP, Python, Java, MongoDB, MySQL

DevOps UX Design

Git, AWS, Docker, Heroku, Linux Adobe XD, Figma, Balsamiq Mockups, Photoshop

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Full Stack JavaScript Developer, Fiverr □

March 2019 - Present

- Built web apps for clients with MERN stack
- Improved static websites performance and user experience by converting them to Single Page Applications

Mobile Developer Intern, PYNTOPYN Technologies ☑

March 2020 -August 2020

- Built a food scanning mobile app with React Native and Expo SDK
- Fixed responsiveness issues by creating custom auto-scaling components
- Collaborated with backend developers and implemented bug fixes
- Built prototype design with InVision Studio

UI/UX Designer Intern, Kollab Agency □

July 2019 -

• Built prototype design for an e-wallet mobile application using Adobe XD

September 2019

Converted design to HTML and CSS components

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Software Engineering,

2016 – Present

National Institute of Applied Sciences and Technology

Minor in DevOps

Baccalaureate in Computer Science, Farhat Hached High School

2012 - 2016

PROJECTS

Chatrooms, A real-time chat app that allows you to create private chat rooms that get destroyed after a time limit. □

- Built the frontend and routing using React
- Implemented chat mechanism with Express, Node, and Socket.io
- Deployed server on Heroku

HackerNews Clone, *A clone of the hackernews website* □

- Built the frontend with React
- Implemented search functionality with highlighted search keywords on result pages
- · Deployed the application on Github pages